I was gonna say that's excellent like
you know the members need to know how to
do that if somebody wanted to get
lessons from you how would they go about
doing that so I have an online course
that I've just created you can go to
power of the Lamb calm mm-hmm power of
the line calm that's my website and
you'll be able to see the different
courses but this is all the photo
theology course okay and and you'll be
able to see what I have online you can
sign up for those courses or you can
just sign up for our emails or give us
your email and sign up for our
newsletter and get more information on
those courses but the purpose of that
course is to basically instruct people
how to do this themselves which leads me
to my dimensions yes dimensions so most
people there are five dimensions of
Bible study in what I call photo
theology so these are the five
dimensions there is a literal dimension
there is the Christ dimension that would
be the second dimension the third
dimension is the me dimension mmm the
fourth dimension is the church dimension
and the fifth dimension is the heaven
dimension okay so what does that mean
first dimension is this what is the text
literally saying right Exodus 20:5 yeah
I was gonna say can we take a text and
run extension let them make me a
sanctuary that I may dwell among them
okay so Exodus 20:5 verse eight is
talking about this literal temple that
was built back there in the wilderness
it's literal sanctuary built back there
in a wilderness by Moses had a holy
place most holy place out of court etc
that is the first dimension I'm simply
looking at the literal building that was
back there in the in the wilderness when
the children of Israel left Egypt the
second dimension is the Christ dimension
hmm let them make me a sanctuary that I
may dwell among them Wow Wow Wow check
this out the sanctuary was located in
the
enter of the 12 tribes oh whoa Volvo
anywhere the century the sanctuary was
to lead the twelve so when God was
leading the children of Israel the cloud
would hover over them and the sanctuary
would go before them so okay Jesus said
destroy this temple and I'll raise it up
again in three days the Bible says of
Jesus that his name would be Immanuel
meaning with let them make me a
sanctuary that I may dwell with among
them ah
so just as a sanctuary dwelt in the
midst of the twelve in the Old Testament
literal dimension in the second
dimension Christ is the temple Christ is
the sanctuary
dwelling among the twelve disciples he
got it now well what about the third
dimension how does this relate to me ah
no you not that you the Holy Ghost and
that the Spirit of God dwells in you ah
I get it now in a literal century
Shekinah glory in a temple in the second
dimension the spirit of his father in
him in the third dimension the Holy
Spirit in me yes from one tech from one
text that's amazing from one text uh-huh
right what about the fourth dimension
what dimension is that are we playing
concentrate mention is the church
dimension okay okay so now we all are
lively stones that are brought together
to form the temple of the Lord to form
the house of God the entire church is a
symbol
or the center is a symbol of the entire
church we are all building the Church of
God the house of God we are stones that
make up the house of God so first
dimension Exodus 25 verse 8 literal
temple second dimension price the temple
third dimension I am a temple fourth
dimension all of us together make the
temple mm-hmm the fifth dimension is the
heavenly dimension ah heavenly sanctuary
[Music]
so now check this out I can take from
one text exodus 25:8 and preach five
different sermons Wow I'm gonna preach
just on the literal temple and all the
symbolism of the literal temple but
guess what after that sermon I'm gonna
do a five part series after that series
I'm gonna do a whole message on how
Christ was the temple and then after
that I'm gonna do another whole message
on how we are I am the temple and that's
what I'm gonna do another message about
how the church is the temple gods we
have to work together because if we're
not working together we cannot complete
the building of the temple and now I'm
thinking hey wait a minute what was
nehemiah and you know these guys and the
old testicle to do they were called to
rebuild the temple because when the
temple is finally built guess what Jesus
the Spirit of God fills the temple when
the temple is built all of a sudden I'm
thinking whoa so you mean when the
church is complete Jesus the latter rain
comes and fills the temple right you can
now take from one text and here's the
thing most people read the Bible in two
dimensions yes what is it literally
saying and what does it mean from me
mm-hmm
you are missing out to me the most
powerful dimension is the second
dimension the Christ dimension but think
about how much you are missing out when
you don't read the Bible in the second
dimension the fourth dimension the fifth
dimension so what I discovered is that
I'm reading a text and someone else is
reading the same text and I'm reading
the text and
going while the other person's reading
the text and they're like what and you
know I'm not saying that in a you know
like look at me type of way I'm just
saying because I'm reading the text in
five dimensions mm-hmm whilst the other
person is reading the text in one
dimension maybe two you miss out on so
much yeah and and all God is really
trying to do is he's trying to open our
eyes so that we can see alright I share
this story very often when I was I
remember once I was probably but not
once I was nineteen I remember one time
at the age of 19 I was walking through
the mall with some of my friends and we
ended up walking by this group of people
who were like oh look at that picture
and I'm like look what it caught my
attention so I walked over and they're
looking at this big picture of nothing
but zigzag lines and I'm like I think
that's crazy like what are you getting
so excited about and someone saw me like
you know looking at them crazy and they
were like you got to do this thing with
your eyes and so I'm like do this thing
with my eyes so I start trying to do all
kinds of stuff with my eyes and suddenly
my eyes focus in on one point of the
picture and suddenly it became a 3d
image and when I moved the image would
move and I was like I mean I was like
losing it like many of us when we pick
up the Bible all we see are zigzag lines
[Music]
mm-hmm why is the story in the Bible
right I don't get this what what is it
saying mm-hmm
but when we do that thing with our eyes
photo theology when we learn to focus
our eyes in on Jesus all of a sudden
that story that was like yeah you know
what this is about all of a sudden it
becomes a 3d image and now we're like
whoa what in the world yeah
yes and that's the fire like if you were
required to study something that you
found no you know I from what many of us
studying the Bible's like that is saying
man I must now study the Bible yeah you
know and it's a burden something to us
they're like oh boy got to do this again
the Bible should be it is the most
exciting book that I have ever read
mm-hmm and that's how we need to
approach the Scriptures we need to
approach the Scriptures expecting you
know I tell people all the time
hey when you read a scripture just get
excited what just get excited excited
because God is going to show you
something if you're open to it and
here's the thing you know when I read
the Bible and I tell people all this all
the time I don't try to find new truth
my objective is not to find new truth
anything you've ever heard me say is
probably something that you already know
the end conclusion don't look at me like
that the end it's something you already
know right you already know that Jesus
came into the world because of our sins
and that he died so that we might live
you already know that you just heard it
in a new package mm-hmm so the new
package is what was like whoa so you
mean we just saw the same thing from the
story of David this messed-up story of
David and that's we can see the same
thing there this is this is what I
believe truth does this is what God does
he shows us the same truth from a
thousand different angles it's not new
light it's not new truth it's the same
old truth but from a thousand different
angles yeah and we have to be careful
that we don't go out trying to find new
truth because that's how people end up
getting in trouble right yeah I'm trying
to find something new yeah that no one
else has seen before and what else is
found before and now all of a sudden
it's like yeah you know what I found
this truth and if you don't believe it
you know God is not working through you
yeah right and we have that soul you
hear about that so often so this is not
looking for new truth is
just saying God show me this the same
old truths but from a new perspective
yes yes